<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Grafana Blog</title>
  <subtitle>Blog posts on Grafana, Metrics, Graphite, Monitoring, Build measure learn</subtitle>
  <id>http://grafana.org/blog</id>
  <link href="http://grafana.org/blog"/>
  <link href="http://grafana.org/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-03-30T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Grafana</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 3.0 Beta Released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2016/03/31/grafana-3-0-beta-released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2016/03/31/grafana-3-0-beta-released.html</id>
    <published>2016-03-30T17:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2016-03-31T09:56:42-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is the day! We are pleased to announce that Grafana 3.0 beta
is released along with a preview of &lt;a href="http://grafana.net"&gt;Grafana.net&lt;/a&gt;! Since our last release
approximately 3 months ago, we’ve been extremely busy. This is the biggest
update to Grafana ever, with over 1500 commits by over 30 contributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read on below to learn more about what’s new in 3.0 or:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="text-center"&gt;
&lt;a class="button secondary radius" href="/download"&gt;Download Grafana 3.0&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;a class="button primary radius" href="http://play.grafana.org" target="_blank"&gt;Live Demo&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="release-highlights"&gt;Release Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="commercial-support"&gt;Commercial Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commercial Support subscriptions for Grafana are now &lt;a href="https://grafana.net/support/plans/"&gt;generally available&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raintank is committed to a 100% open-source strategy for Grafana. We
do not want to go down the “open core” route. If your organization
finds Grafana valuable, please consider purchasing a subscription. Get
direct support, bug fixes, and training from the core Grafana team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="plugins"&gt;Plugins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the popularity of Grafana continuing to accelerate, it has been
challenging to keep up with all the requests for new features, new
panels, new data sources, and new functionality. Saying “no” so often
has been frustrating, especially for an open source project with such
a vibrant community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team felt that it was time to dramatically improve extensibility
through plugin support. Grafana 3.0 comes with a completely revamped
plugin SDK / API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve refactored our &lt;strong&gt;Data Source&lt;/strong&gt; plugin architecture and added
two new plugin types:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panel&lt;/strong&gt; plugins let you add new panel types for your Dashboards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;App&lt;/strong&gt; plugins bundle &lt;strong&gt;Panels&lt;/strong&gt; plugins, &lt;strong&gt;Data Sources&lt;/strong&gt; plugins,
Dashboards, and Grafana &lt;strong&gt;Pages&lt;/strong&gt;. Apps are a great way to provide an
entire experience right within Grafana.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="grafana-net"&gt;Grafana.net&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/v3.0/grafana_net_tour.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A preview of &lt;a href="http://grafana.net"&gt;Grafana.net&lt;/a&gt; is launching along with this release. We
think it’s the perfect compliment to Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana.net currently offers a central repository where the community
can come together to discover and share plugins (Data Sources, Panels,
Apps) and Dashboards for Grafana 3.0 and above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also working on a hosted Graphite-compatible Data Source that
will be optimized for use with Grafana. It’ll be easy to combine your
existing Data Source(s) with this OpenSaaS option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Grafana.net will also be a hub to manage all your Grafana
instances. You’ll be able to monitor their health and availability,
perform Dashboard backups, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana.net will officially launch along with the stable version of
Grafana 3.0, but &lt;a href=http://www.grafana.net&gt;check out the preview
and sign up for an account&lt;/a&gt; in the meantime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="grafana-cli"&gt;grafana-cli&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 3.0 comes with a new command line tool called grafana-cli. You
can easily install plugins from Grafana.net with it. For
example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;grafana-cli install grafana-pie-chart-panel
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id="improved-personalization"&gt;Improved Personalization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana will track recently viewed Dashboards. The dashboard list
panel can show these on your home dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="improved-playlists"&gt;Improved Playlists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now save Playlists, and start them by using a Playlist URL. If
you update a running Playlist, it will update after its next cycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is powerful as it allows you to remote control Grafana. If you
have a big TV display showing Grafana in your company lobby, create a
playlist named Lobby, and start it on the computer connected to the
Lobby TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now change the Lobby playlist and have the dashboards shown in
the Lobby update accordingly, automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The playlist does not even have to contain multiple Dashboards; you
can use this feature to reload the whole Dashboard (and Grafana)
periodically and remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also make Playlists dynamic by using Dashboard &lt;strong&gt;tags&lt;/strong&gt; to
define the Playlist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/v3/playlist.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="improved-ui"&gt;Improved UI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve always tried to focus on a good looking, usable, and responsive
UI. We’ve continued to pay a lot of attention to these areas in this
release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 3.0 has a dramatically updated UI that not only looks better
but also has a number of usability improvements. The side menu now
works as a dropdown that you can pin to the side. The Organization /
Profile / Sign out side menu links have been combined into an on hover
slide out menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, all the forms and the layouts of all pages have been
updated to look and flow better, and be much more consistent. There
are literally hundreds of UI improvements and refinements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the new side menu in action:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/v3/menu.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s the new look for Dashboard settings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/v3/dashboard_settings.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org" target="_blank"&gt;Play
Site&lt;/a&gt; to get a feel for some of the UI changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="improved-annotations"&gt;Improved Annotations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to define a link in each annotation. You can hover
over the link and click the annotation text. This feature is very
useful for linking to particular commits or tickets where more
detailed information can be presented to the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/v3/annotation_links.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="prometheus-influxdb-and-opentsdb-improvements"&gt;Prometheus, InfluxDB, and OpenTSDB improvements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three of these popular included Data Sources have seen a variety
of improvements in this release. Here are some highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="prometheus"&gt;Prometheus&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Prometheus Data Source now supports annotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="influxdb"&gt;InfluxDB&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now select the InfluxDB policy from the query editor.
&lt;img src="/assets/img/v3/influxdb_policy.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 3.0 also comes with support for InfluxDB 0.11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="opentsdb"&gt;OpenTSDB&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenTSDB 2.2 is better supported and now supports millisecond precision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="improved-code-and-reduced-technical-debt"&gt;Improved code, and reduced technical debt&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The styling system has seen a massive update and clean-up. Grafana 1.x
and 2.x were built on a shaky and old style foundation based on
Bootstrap 2.3, followed by a Bootswatch dark theme, followed by many
custom overrides. This has been completely removed, and we have
switched to a modern and custom SASS based style foundation. In
addition, much of the code has been migrated to ES6 and Typescript.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These changes dramatically improve the maintainability  of the code
going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="where-s-alerting"&gt;Where’s alerting?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are aware that many of you are waiting for the alerting feature,
and regrettably it didn’t make it into this beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we understand that many are disappointed, and anxious to get
alerting in Grafana, the team strongly felt that improving
extensibility and addressing technical debt were more important in the
short term, and will give us a stronger base to build alerting on top
of. We have spent a lot of effort making sure that the code base
remains modern and of high quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did not take this decision lightly, and hope that our users
understand the logic behind our choice. Once Grafana 3.0 stable is
released, we will be circling back on Alerting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="breaking-changes"&gt;Breaking changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dashboards from v2.6 are compatible; no manual updates should be necessary. There could
be some edge case scenarios where dashboards using templating could stop working.
If that is the case just enter the edit view for the template variable and hit Update button.
This is due to a simplification of the variable format system where template variables are
now stored without any formatting (glob/regex/etc), this is done on the fly when the
variable is interpolated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plugin API: The plugin API has changed so if you are using a custom
data source (or panel) they need to be updated as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;InfluxDB 0.8: This data source is no longer included in releases,
you can still install manually from &lt;a href="http://grafana.net"&gt;Grafana.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;KairosDB: This data source has also no longer shipped with Grafana,
you can install it manually from &lt;a href="http://grafana.net"&gt;Grafana.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="changelog"&gt;CHANGELOG&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a detailed list and link to github issues for everything included
in the 3.0 release please view the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md"&gt;CHANGELOG.md&lt;/a&gt;
file.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana- It's Rocket Science</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2016/01/19/Grafana-Its-Rocket-Science.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2016/01/19/Grafana-Its-Rocket-Science.html</id>
    <published>2016-01-18T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2016-03-02T03:09:54-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Raj Dutt</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/v2/rocket_science_twitter.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href="http://raintank.io" target="_blank"&gt;raintank&lt;/a&gt;, all our software is open source. We haven’t talked much about how the whole stack will fit together (more on that soon…), but starting with &lt;a href="http://www.grafana.org" target="_blank"&gt;Grafana&lt;/a&gt;, every &lt;a href="https://github.com/raintank/litmus-plugin" target="_blank"&gt;piece&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/raintank/raintank-metric" target="_blank"&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://github.com/raintank/raintank-probe" target="_blank"&gt;it&lt;/a&gt; is being developed in the open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our core revenue model is OpenSaaS: We couple our software with optional hosted services that we provide. These services are also powered by software that is open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of our users will simply choose to download our open source software, and won&amp;rsquo;t pay us anything. Many will choose to host our stack with another provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That may sound alarming to a potential raintank investor, but it’s actually totally OK, and expected. Not only does open source help us create much better software, but if done right it gives us the most amazing distribution channel that money can’t buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep up with the awesome ways that Grafana is being used, let alone by whom. Difficulty identifying  your users and successes isn’t an issue most software or SaaS companies face, but it’s pretty endemic in open source. It&amp;rsquo;s something that we&amp;rsquo;re focusing on improving this year at raintank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many situations, we find out that someone is using Grafana in the most indirect ways: a tweet, a job posting that mentions it, a blog post, an issue filed, a PR, or sometimes even a thank you note.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always a thrill to find out when someone cool is finding value in your software. One of the biggest thrills so far came a few days ago, when our very own Dieter Plaetinck noticed  Grafana on a screen at the SpaceX Launch Control Center during their recent Falcon 9 launch:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/v2/grafana-spotted.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Watch &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/ANv5UfZsvZQ"&gt;The Falcon has landed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ANv5UfZsvZQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bunch of us at raintank are huge fans of SpaceX, and follow the launches regularly. We’d love to learn more about what they&amp;rsquo;re doing with Grafana (and have already contacted them). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, knowing that they’ve gotten some small value out of Grafana, and it&amp;rsquo;s up on screen visualizing their measurement data, is just an awesome feeling. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onwards and upwards, open source, Grafana, and SpaceX!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style="font-size:75%"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main photo courtesy of NASA&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 

&lt;h4 id="thanks-to-project-sponsors"&gt;Thanks to project sponsors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://raintank.io"&gt;Raintank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mediamath.com/OpenSource"&gt;Mediamath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 2.6.0 Released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/12/14/Grafana-2-6-Released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/12/14/Grafana-2-6-Released.html</id>
    <published>2015-12-13T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2016-01-12T11:10:43-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are proud to announce the v2.6.0 stable release. This release includes a new &lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/reference/table_panel"&gt;Table panel&lt;/a&gt;,
an example of which you can see below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/table-panel.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new flexible panel enables multiple ways for visualizing time series and logs in a tabular format. The release also includes a new InfluxDB query editor,
support for Elasticsearch pipeline aggregations, support for multiple Cloudwatch credentials and a ton of minor
fixes and improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/guides/whats-new-in-v2-6"&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s New In Grafana v2.6&lt;/a&gt; article
for more info on new features. There is also a &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org/dashboard/db/new-features-in-v2-6"&gt;Demo dashboard&lt;/a&gt;
at the demo site where you can play with the new panel and InfluxDB editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="text-center"&gt;
  &lt;a class="button secondary radius" href="/download"&gt;Download Grafana 2.6 now&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upgrading from any previous 2.x version is safe, dashboards are backward compatible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/installation/debian/"&gt;Installing on Debian / Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/installation/rpm/"&gt;Installing on RPM-based Linux (CentOS, Fedora, OpenSuse, RedHat)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/installation/docker/"&gt;Installing via Docker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="changelog"&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a detailed list and link to github issues for everything included in the 2.6 release please
view the &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md"&gt;CHANGELOG.md&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 id="thanks-to-project-sponsors"&gt;Thanks to project sponsors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://raintank.io"&gt;Raintank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mediamath.com/OpenSource"&gt;Mediamath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 2.6 Beta Released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/12/04/Grafana-2-6-Beta-Released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/12/04/Grafana-2-6-Beta-Released.html</id>
    <published>2015-12-03T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2016-01-12T11:10:43-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="release-highlights"&gt;Release highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/v2.6/header.png" class="no-shadow"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release adds a new panel, namely the top requested &lt;strong&gt;Table Panel&lt;/strong&gt;. Yes it is
finally here! The reason for the beta release status is because the release also
includes a new and more powerful InfluxDB query editor.  This new editor works very
differently from the previous one and requires more feedback and testing
before a stable release can be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="text-center"&gt;
  &lt;a class="button secondary radius" href="/download"&gt;Download Grafana 2.6 beta now&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main documentation pages have yet to be updated with information about how to use
the new table panel and the new InfluxDB editor so for now refer to this blog post for guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="table-panel"&gt;Table Panel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new table panel is very flexible, supporting both multiple modes for time series as well as for
table, annotation and raw JSON data. It also provides date formating and value formating and coloring options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="time-series-to-rows"&gt;Time series to rows&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the most simple mode you can turn time series to rows. This means you get a &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Time&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Metric&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Value&lt;/code&gt; column.
Where &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Metric&lt;/code&gt; is the name of the time series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/v2.6/table_ts_to_rows.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="table-transform"&gt;Table Transform&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above you see the options tab for the &lt;strong&gt;Table Panel&lt;/strong&gt;. The most important option is the &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;To Table Transform&lt;/code&gt;.
This option controls how the result of the metric/data query is turned into a table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="column-styles"&gt;Column Styles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The column styles allow you control how dates and numbers are formatted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="time-series-to-columns"&gt;Time series to columns&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This transform allows you to take multiple time series and group them by time. Which will result in a &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Time&lt;/code&gt; column
and a column for each time series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/v2.6/table_ts_to_columns.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the screenshot above you can see how the same time series query as in the previous example can be transformed into
a different table by changing the &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;To Table Transform&lt;/code&gt; to  &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Time series to columns&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="time-series-to-aggregations"&gt;Time series to aggregations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This transform works very similar to the legend values in the Graph panel. Each series gets its own row. In the Options
tab you can select which aggregations you want using the plus button the Columns section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/v2.6/table_ts_to_aggregations.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to think about how accurate the aggregations will be. It depends on what aggregation is used in the time series query,
how many data points are fetched, etc. The time series aggregations are calculated by Grafana after aggregation is performed
by the time series database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="raw-logs-queries"&gt;Raw logs queries&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to show documents from Elasticsearch pick &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Raw Document&lt;/code&gt; as the first metric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/v2.6/elastic_raw_doc.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This in combination with the &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;JSON Data&lt;/code&gt; table transform will allow you to pick which fields in the document
you want to show in the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/v2.6/table_json_data.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="elasticsearch-aggregations"&gt;Elasticsearch aggregations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also make Elasticsearch aggregation queries without a &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Date Histogram&lt;/code&gt;. This allows you to
use Elasticsearch metric aggregations to get accurate aggregations for the selected time range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/v2.6/elastic_aggregations.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="annotations"&gt;Annotations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The table can also show any annotations you have enabled in the dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/v2.6/table_annotations.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="the-new-influxdb-editor"&gt;The New InfluxDB Editor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new InfluxDB editor is a lot more flexible and powerful. It supports nested functions, like &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;derivative&lt;/code&gt;.
It also uses the same technique as the Graphite query editor in that it presents nested functions as chain of function
transformations. It tries to simplify and unify the complicated nature of InfluxDB&amp;rsquo;s query language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/v2.6/influxdb_editor_v3.gif"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new editor also allows you to remove group by time and select &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;raw&lt;/code&gt; table data. Which is very useful
in combination with the new Table panel to show raw log data stored in InfluxDB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/v2.6/table_influxdb_logs.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="breaking-changes"&gt;Breaking changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/strong&gt;: Manual json edited queries are not supported any more (They very barely worked in 2.5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="changelog"&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a detailed list and link to github issues for everything included in the 2.6 release please
view the &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md"&gt;CHANGELOG.md&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="/download"&gt;Download Grafana 2.6 beta now&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org/dashboard/db/new-features-in-v2-6"&gt;Demo dashboard for Grafana 2.6 features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 id="download-grafana-2-6-beta-now"&gt;&lt;a href="http://grafana.org/download"&gt;Download Grafana 2.6 beta now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id="thanks-to-project-sponsors"&gt;Thanks to project sponsors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://raintank.io"&gt;Raintank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mediamath.com/OpenSource"&gt;Mediamath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 2.5 Released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/10/28/Grafana-2-5-Released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/10/28/Grafana-2-5-Released.html</id>
    <published>2015-10-27T17:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2016-01-12T11:10:43-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="release-highlights"&gt;Release highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img class="no-shadow" src="/assets/img/blog/grafana_2_5_graphic.png" alt="New Time picker"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="text-center"&gt;
  &lt;a class="button primary radius" href="/download"&gt;Download Grafana 2.5 now&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an exciting release, and we want to share some of the highlights. The release includes many
fixes and enhancements to all areas of Grafana, like new Data Sources, a new and improved timepicker,
user invites, panel resize handles and improved InfluxDB and OpenTSDB support, LDAP improvements, Graph
panel units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-time-range-controls"&gt;New time range controls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/timepicker.png" alt="New Time picker"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new timepicker with room for more quick ranges as well as new types of relative ranges, like &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Today&lt;/code&gt;,
&lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;The day so far&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;This day last week&lt;/code&gt;. Also an improved time &amp;amp; calendar picker that now works
correctly in UTC mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="elasticsearch"&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/elasticsearch_metrics_ex1.png" alt="Elasticsearch example"&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release brings a fully featured query editor for Elasticsearch. You will now be able to visualize
logs or any kind of data stored in Elasticserarch. The query editor allows you to build both simple
and complex queries for logs or metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compute metrics from your documents, supported Elasticsearch aggregations:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Count, Avg, Min, Max, Sum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Percentiles, Std Dev, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group by multiple terms or filters

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specify group by options like Top 5 based on Avg @value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto completion for field names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Query only relevant indices based on time pattern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alias patterns for short readable series names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try the new Elasticsearch query editor on the &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org/dashboard/db/elasticsearch-metrics"&gt;play.grafana.org&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="cloudwatch"&gt;CloudWatch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/cloudwatch.png" alt="Cloudwatch editor"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.5 ships with a new CloudWatch datasource that will allow you to query and visualize CloudWatch
metrics directly from Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rich editor with auto completion for metric names, namespaces and dimensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templating queries for generic dashboards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alias patterns for short readable series names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="prometheus"&gt;Prometheus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/prometheus_editor.png" alt="Prometheus editor"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.5 ships with a new Prometheus datasource that will allow you to query and visualize data
stored in Prometheus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="mix-different-data-sources"&gt;Mix different data sources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/mixed_data.png" alt="Mix data sources in the same dashboard or in the same graph!"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In previous releases you have been able to mix different data sources on the same dashboard. In v2.5 you
will be able to mix them on the same graph! You can enable this by selecting the built in &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;-- Mixed --&lt;/code&gt; data source.
When selected this will allow you to specify data source on a per query basis. This will, for example, allow you
to plot metrics from different Graphite servers on the same Graph or plot data from Elasticsearch alongside
data from Prometheus. Mixing different data sources on the same graph works for any data source, even custom ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="panel-resize-handles"&gt;Panel Resize handles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/panel_resize.gif" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release adds resize handles to the the bottom right corners of panels making is easy to resize both width and height.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="user-invites"&gt;User invites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/org_invite.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version also brings some new features for user management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organization admins can now invite new users (via email or manually via invite link)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can signup using invite link and get automatically added to invited organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User signup workflow can (if enabled) contain an email verification step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/issues/2353"&gt;#2353&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="miscellaneous-improvements"&gt;Miscellaneous improvements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InfluxDB query editor now supports math and AS expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InfluxDB query editor now supports custom group by interval&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Panel drilldown link is easier to reach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LDAP improvements (can now search for group membership if your LDAP server does not support memberOf attribute)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More units for graph and singlestat panel (Length, Volume, Temperature, Pressure, Currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admin page for all organizations (remove / edit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="breaking-changes"&gt;Breaking changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been some changes to the data source plugin API. If you are using a custom plugin check that there is an update for it before you upgrade. Also
the new time picker does not currently support custom quick ranges like the last one did. This will likely be added in a
future release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="changelog"&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a detailed list and link to github issues for everything included in the 2.5 release please
view the &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md"&gt;CHANGELOG.md&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-39-s-next-for-grafana"&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next for Grafana?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this release does not excite you then maybe the next one will. Starting next week work on integrating
alerting into Grafana, in a non-intrusive and composable way, will begin. We have already spent a lot of
time discussing this feature with the Grafana user community, done UI mock ups, etc. You can join the
discussion and view mocks ups at &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/issues/2209"&gt;Issue #2209&lt;/a&gt;. Another top
priority will be a table panel and more ways to visualize metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 id="download-grafana-2-5-now"&gt;&lt;a href="http://grafana.org/download"&gt;Download Grafana 2.5 now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id="thanks-to-project-sponsors"&gt;Thanks to project sponsors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://raintank.io"&gt;Raintank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mediamath.com/OpenSource"&gt;Mediamath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 2.1 Released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/08/04/Grafana-2-1-Released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/08/04/Grafana-2-1-Released.html</id>
    <published>2015-08-03T17:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2016-01-12T11:10:43-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="no-shadow" src="/assets/img/blog/new-in-grafana-v2-1.png" alt="what's new in Grafana 2.1"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been working to implement many of the features you&amp;rsquo;ve requested since the release of 2.0, and are
excited to announce the release of Grafana 2.1 today. We recommend that all Grafana users upgrade to this release.
Grafana 2.1 brings improvements in three core areas: dashboarding, authentication, and data sources.
As with every Grafana release, there is a whole slew of new features, enhancements, and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://grafana.org/download/" target="_blank"&gt;Download Grafana 2.1 now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re excited about this release, and want to share some of the highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id="more-dynamic-dashboards"&gt;More Dynamic Dashboards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Templating system is one of the most powerful and well-used features of Grafana.
The 2.1 release brings numerous improvements that make dashboards more dynamic than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="multi-value-template-variables"&gt;Multi-Value Template Variables&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A template variable with Multi-Value enabled allows for the selection of multiple values at the same time.
These variables can then be used in any panel to make them more dynamic, and to give you the perfect view of your data.
Multi-Value variables is also enabling the new &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;row repeat&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;panel repeat&lt;/code&gt; feature described below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Multi-Value Select" alt="Multi-Value Select" src="/assets/img/blog/multi-select.gif" /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="repeating-rows-and-panels"&gt;Repeating Rows and Panels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s now possible to create a Dashboard that automatically adds (or removes) both rows and panels based
on selected variable values. Any row or any panel can be configured to repeat (duplicate itself) based
on a multi-value template variable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Repeating Rows and Panels" alt="Repeating Rows and Panels" src="/assets/img/blog/panel-row-repeat.gif" /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="dashboard-links-amp-navigation"&gt;Dashboard Links &amp;amp; Navigation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support better navigation between dashboards, it&amp;rsquo;s now possible to create custom and dynamic links from individual
panels to appropriate Dashboards. You also have the ability to create flexible top-level links on any
given Dashboard thanks to the new Dashboard navigation bar feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Dashboard Links" alt="Dashboard Links" src="/assets/img/blog/dash_links.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dashboard links can be added under dashboard settings. Either defined as static URLs with a custom icon or as dynamic
dashboard links or dropdowns based on custom dashboard search query. These links appear in the same
row under the top menu where template variables appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="better-local-dashboard-support"&gt;Better local Dashboard support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana can now index Dashboards saved locally as JSON from a given directory. These file based dashboards
will appear in the regular dashboard search along regular DB dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Saving local dashboards back the folder is not supported; this feature is meant for statically generated JSON dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-authentication-options"&gt;New Authentication Options&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New authentication methods add numerous options to manage users, roles and organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="ldap-support"&gt;LDAP support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This highly requested feature now allows your Grafana users to login with their LDAP credentials.
You can also specify mappings between LDAP group memberships and Grafana Organization user roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="basic-auth-support"&gt;Basic Auth Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now authenticate against the Grafana API utilizing a simple username and password with basic HTTP authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; This can be useful for provisioning and config management systems that need
to utilize the API without having to create an API key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="auth-proxy-support"&gt;Auth Proxy Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now authenticate utilizing a header (eg. X-Authenticated-User, or X-WEBAUTH-USER)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this can be useful in situations with reverse proxies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-read-only-editor-user-role"&gt;New “Read-only Editor” User Role&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a new User role available in this version of Grafana: “Read-only Editor”. This role behaves just
like the Viewer role does in Grafana 2.0.  That is you can edit graphs and queries but not save dashboards.
The Viewer role has been modified in Grafana 2.1 so that users assigned this role can no longer edit panels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id="data-source-improvements"&gt;Data source Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="influxdb-0-9-support"&gt;InfluxDB 0.9 Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.1 now comes with full support for InfluxDB 0.9. There is a new query editor designed from scratch
for the new features InfluxDB 0.9 enables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="InfluxDB Editor" alt="InfluxDB Editor" src="/assets/img/blog/influx_09_editor_anim.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="opentsdb-improvements"&gt;OpenTSDB Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana OpenTSDB data source now supports template variable values queries. This means you can create
template variables that fetches the values from OpenTSDB (for example metric names, tag names, or tag values).
The query editor is also enhanced to limiting tags by metric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; OpenTSDB config option tsd.core.meta.enable_realtime_ts must enabled for OpenTSDB lookup api)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-data-source-kairosdb"&gt;New Data Source: KairosDB&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cassandra backed time series database KairosDB is now supported in Grafana out of the box. Thank you to
&lt;a href="https://github.com/masaori335" target="_blank"&gt;masaori335&lt;/a&gt; for his hard work in getting it to this point. Also thanks
to &lt;a href="https://github.com/rdettai"&gt;Remi Dettai&lt;/a&gt; for the initial implementation of the KairosDB data source plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id="panel-improvements"&gt;Panel Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.1 gives you even more flexibility customizing how individual panels render.
Overriding the colors of specific series using regular expressions, changing how series stack,
and allowing string values will help you better understand your data at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="graph-panel"&gt;Graph Panel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Define series color using regex rule. This is useful when you have templated graphs with series names
that change depending selected template variables. Using a regex style override rule you could
for example make all series that contain the word &lt;strong&gt;CPU&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;red&lt;/code&gt; and assigned to the second y axis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Define series color using regex rule" alt="Define series color using regex rule" src="/assets/img/blog/regex_color_override.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New series style override, negative-y transform and stack groups. Negative y tranform is
very useful if you want to plot a series on the negative y scale without affecting the legend values like min or max or
the values shown in the hover tooltip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Negative-y Transform" alt="Negative-y Transform" src="/assets/img/blog/negative-y.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Negative-y Transform" alt="Negative-y Transform" src="/assets/img/blog/negative-y-form.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="singlestat-panel"&gt;Singlestat Panel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now support string values. Useful for time series database like InfluxDB that supports
string values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="changelog"&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a detailed list and link to github issues for everything included in the 2.1 release please
view the &lt;a href="&amp;quot;https://github.com/grafana/grafana/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md&amp;quot;"&gt;CHANGELOG.md&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="download-grafana-2-1-now"&gt;&lt;a href="http://grafana.org/download"&gt;Download Grafana 2.1 now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id="demo-dashboard-for-grafana-2-1-features"&gt;&lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org/dashboard/db/new-features-in-v2-1"&gt;Demo dashboard for Grafana 2.1 features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="thanks-to-project-sponsors"&gt;Thanks to project sponsors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mediamath.com/OpenSource"&gt;Mediamath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="subscribe-to-project-updates"&gt;Subscribe to project updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;section class="newsletter"&gt;
  &lt;form action="http://grafana.us8.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=2aeb5711db2aececc990be536&amp;amp;id=5585d37ecc" method="post" id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" class="validate" target="_blank"&gt;
    &lt;row class="collapse"&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-10 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" class="email" id="mce-EMAIL" placeholder="email address"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-2 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="submit" value="Subscribe" name="subscribe" id="mc-embedded-subscribe" class="button postfix"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/row&gt;
  &lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
